Weishan He

+1 6692859872 • weishanhe0@gmail.com • Beachwood, OH • Website • LinkedIn • GitHub

PROFILE

Experienced full-stack data scientist with 3+ years of expertise in Python, SQL, Machine Learning, NLP, and A/B testing. Collaborated to build recommendation systems and drive analyses, achieving a 30% increase in sign-up rate, 10% reduction in excess inventory, and a 10% boost in marketing sentiment score

Technical Skills: Python (PyTorch, Pandas, Scikit-learn, Seaborn, etc.), SQL, R, Shell Script, Tableau (portfolio), Looker, Git, Poetry, Docker, Google Cloud Platform, AWS, Hadoop/PySpark, FastAPI

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Andela Inc., a tech company connecting global talent with leading organizations worldwide Data Scientist

Remote, USA

Aug. 2022 – Apr. 2023

- Spearheaded experimentation, utilizing **Frequentist** and **Bayesian** approaches to design and analyze impactful **A/B testing**, achieving a 30% increase in the sign-up rate
- Pioneered a recommendation engine using tree-based machine learning models and **NLP** to automate 30% of hiring events, reducing time-to-hire by 20%
- Engineered data pipeline using **Python** and **SQL** to query, validate, convert, and calculate features in batch, reducing preprocessing time by 40%
- Revamped training pipeline for diverse models, feature selection, calibration, and continuous updates, cutting training time by 50%
- Implemented a **Docker** container, **API**, and Git Tag to seamlessly deliver the model to the engineering team
- Created **Looker** dashboards to monitor key metrics of recommendation engine, demonstrating parity with human recruiters in converting talent profile views to scheduling interview

 ${\bf UC\ Davis\ Health\ Pharmacy},\ a\ practicum\ of\ the\ UC\ Davis\ MSBA\ program$

Remote, USA

Data Analyst (Practicum)

Aug. 2021 – Jun. 2022

• Developed **Tableau** dashboards for pharmacists to optimize inventory management, resulting in \$50,000 quarterly cost savings and 10% reduction in excess inventory

quarterly cost savings and 10% reduction in excess inventory

Mininglamp Technology Co., Ltd, a tech company providing data platform and analysis services

Guangzhou, China

Senior Business Analyst

• Conducted **sentiment and topic analysis** on unstructured social media data, boosting sentiment score by 10% and

• Conducted **sentiment and topic analysis** on unstructured social media data, boosting sentiment score by 10% and convincing clients to extend the purchase of social media analysis

Ipsos (China) Consulting Co., Ltd, a market research company

Guangzhou, China

Quantitative Research Executive

Jan. 2018 – Sep. 2019

- Collaborated with the manager to lead cross-functional team of six, completing 16 marketing research projects and generating 20% annual team revenue
- Analyzed online shopping market research data in **Excel**, identifying five high-potential growth scenarios for a projected 15% revenue increase
- Mastered the firm's market segmentation model and enhanced the Usage and Attitude study pitch book, winning a \$80,000 bid

EDUCATION

M.S. in Business Analytics, University of California - Davis

Aug. 2021 – Jun. 2022

B.S. in International Economics and Trade, Shandong University

Sep. 2014 – Jun. 2018

DATA SCIENCE PROJECTS

- Customer Churn Prediction & CLV: applied diff-in-diff to measure the short-term effect of a new feature, and used logistic regression to predict churn and calculate CLV to estimate the long-term effect
- Stock Price Estimation using Deep Learning (LSTM): predicted stock close price using time-series data and stacked LSTM (More Projects)